

Senior Researcher in Robotics https://ori.ox.ac.uk/~bruno bruno@robots.ox.ac.uk

ABOUT ME

I am currently a Senior Researcher in Robotics at the Goal-Oriented Long-Lived Systems (GOALS) Lab, Oxford Robotics Institute, University of Oxford. My research focuses on the intersection of decision making under uncertainty, formal methods and mobile robotics. In particular, I am interested on the use of a combination of techniques from learning, planning and model checking to synthesise intelligent, robust and verifiable behaviour, both for single and for multi-robot systems.

Research Interests

- · Sequential Decision Making under Uncertainty
- · Probabilistic Model Checking
- · Planning for Robotics
- · Multi-Robot Coordination
- · Service Robotics
- · Discrete Event Systems

EDUCATION

Instituto Superior Técnico, Lisbon, Portugal

· PhD in Electrical and Computer Engineering

2009 - 2013

Thesis: Supervision of Discrete Event Systems Based on Temporal Logic Specifications

Advisor: Pedro U. Lima

MSc in Mathematics and Applications

2002 - 2007

Thesis: Linear-Time Temporal Logic Control of Discrete Event Systems

Advisors: Pedro U. Lima, Francisco M. Dionísio

· BSc in Applied Mathematics and Computation

2002-2007

RESEARCH POSITIONS

Oxford Robotics Institute, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK

· Senior Researcher in Robotics September 2018 – Present

· Postdoctoral Research Assistant in Robotics September 2017 – September 2018

University of Birmingham, Birmingham, UK

April 2013 – September 2017

· Postdoctoral Research Fellow in Intelligent Robotics

Örebro University, Örebro, Sweden September 2008 – December 2008

· Research Intern

Instituto Superior Técnico, Lisbon, Portugal March 2008 – August 2008

· Research Intern

CONTRIBUTION TO PROJECTS

University of Oxford

· Offshore Robotics for Certification of Assets (ORCA). UK Research and Innovation

· Robotics and Artificial Intelligence for Nuclear (RAIN). UK Research and Innovation

University of Birmingham

- · Spatio-Temporal Representations and Activities for Cognitive Control in Long-Term Scenarios (STRANDS). EU-FP7
- \cdot Novel Dynamic Vehicle Scheduling and Path Planning Algorithms for Mobile Robotic and AGV Warehouse Order Picking. TSB Smart Award
- · Learning the Structure and Dynamics of Human Environments to Support Intelligent Mobile Robot Behaviour. EPSRC First Grant

TEACHING

University of Oxford

· Lecturer: Probabilistic Model Checking Shared lecturing duties with Marta Kwiatkowska Michaelmas Term 2018

University of Birmingham

· Invited Lectures: Robot Programming	Semester 2 2015/2016, 2016/2017
Delivered two lectures each year on multi-robot coordination	
· Lecturer: Intelligent Robotics	Semester 1 2014/2015
Shared lecturing duties with Chris Burbridge and Lars Kunze	
· Invited Research Lecture: Intelligent Robotics	Semester 1 $2013/2014$
· Demonstrator: Foundations of Computer Science	Semester 1 2013/2014

STUDENT SUPERVISION

University of Oxford	
· PhD Co-Supervisor (w/ Nick Hawes): Charlie Street Topic: AI for Multi-Robot Systems	September 2018 – Present
· PhD Co-Supervisor (w/ Nick Hawes): Marc Rigter Topic: Shared Autonomy with Formal Guarantees	September 2018 – Present
· PhD Co-Supervisor (w/ Nick Hawes): Michael Painter Topic: Multi-Objective Mission Planning	September 2018 – Present
· 4th Year Project Supervisor: Han Zhou Topic: Auctioning for Multi-Robot Coordination	October 2018 – Present

University of Birmingham	
· PhD Co-Supervisor (w/ David Parker and Nick Hawes): Fatma Fart Topic: Simultaneous Task Allocation and Planning under Uncertain	
· PhD Co-Supervisor (w/ Nick Hawes): Lenka Mudrova	June 2014 – September 2017
Topic: Task Scheduling and Merging in Space and Time · MSc Summer Project (w/ Jeremy Wyatt): Milan Tomy	June 2017 – September 2017
Topic: Battery Scheduling in Autonomous Mobile Robots · BSc Final Year Project (w/ Nick Hawes): Joseph Shaw	October 2016 – April 2017
Topic: Auctioning for Multi-Robot Coordination	•
· MSc Summer Project (w/ Nick Hawes): Pedro Elias Topic: Multi-agent Path Finding	June 2015 – September 2015
· MSc Summer Project (w/ Nick Hawes): Eliot Dixon Topic: MDP Models for Mobile Service Robots	June 2014 – September 2014
· MSc Summer Project (w/ Nick Hawes): Ken Poyner Topic: Autonomous Navigation Cost Estimation In Mobile Robots	June 2013 – September 2013
1	

RESEARCH VISITS

Delft University of Technology, Delft, The Netherlands

May 2016 – July 2016

· Host: Matthijs Spaan

University of California, Los Angeles, CA, USA

September 2011 – December 2011

· Host: Paulo Tabuada

University Carlos III de Madrid, Madrid, Spain

March 2010 - June 2010

· Host: Miguel A. Salichs

AWARDED FUNDING

LEaDing Fellows, a Marie Curie COFUND Programme

July 2018

- 2 Year Fellowship
- · Research Proposal: "Cooperative Multi-Robot Transportation Systems with Guaranteed Quality of Service"
- · Declined opportunity and stayed at University of Oxford

LES & EPS PERCAT Career Development Competition, University of Birmingham

March 2016

· Travel support for research visit to TU Delft

Ramsay Research Travel Fund, School of Computer Science, University of Birmingham

March 2016

· Subsistence support for research visit to TU Delft

Fundação para a Ciência e Tecnologia, Portugal

· Funding for PhD student research visit to UCLA

April 2011

· Funding for PhD student research visit to UC3M

November 2009

INVITED TALKS

- · Workshop on Formal Methods in AI, University of Naples Federico II, Naples, Italy February 2017
- \cdot Computer Science Department Seminar Series, University of Liverpool, UK

March 2017

· Robolog Workshop, IRISA, Rennes, France

June 2017

· Full-day Tutorial at 4th Lucia PhD School on AI and Robotics, Lisbon, Portugal September 2017

SERVICE

University of Oxford

 Organiser of the Oxford Robotics Research Group Seminars (w/ Siddharth Narayanaswamy)

May 2018 – Present

 \cdot Engineering Research Associate at Pembroke College

August 2018 – Present

 \cdot Participated in robot demo and Pembroke College Open Day

June 2018

· Lead robot demo at Blenheim Palace, Woodstock, Oxfordshire

January 2019

University of Birmingham

· Participated in several robot demos at various locations, e.g., London's Museum of Natural History, Birmingham's Think Tank, School of Computer Science and University of Birmingham's Open Days 2014-2018

Reviewing

- · Artificial Intelligence (AIJ)
- · IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (TACON)
- · IEEE Robotics & Automation Magazine (RAM)
- · Discrete Event Dynamic Systems (DEDS)
- · IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering (T-ASE)
- · IEEE Control Systems Letters (L-CSS)
- · IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics (SMC)
- · IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Systems (IS)
- · International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) 2017 2019
- · AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2018, 2019
- \cdot International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS) 2014, 2016 2019
- · International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS) 2016 2019
- · European Conference of Artificial Intelligence (ECAI) 2016, 2018
- \cdot International Conference on Tools and Algorithms for the Construction and Analysis of Systems (TACAS) 2017
- · International Symposium on Distributed Autonomous Robotic Systems (DARS) 2014
- · IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2015, 2018
- \cdot IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2015 2018
- · IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC) 2018
- · American Control Conference (ACC) 2016, 2018
- · IEEE International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering (CASE) 2015, 2016
- AAAI Spring Symposium on Integrating Representation, Reasoning, Learning, and Execution for Goal Directed Autonomy - 2018
- Introspective Methods for Reliable Autonomy Workshop @ IROS 2017 Workshop on Autonomous Mobile Service Robots @ IJCAI 2016
- · AI for Long-term Autonomy Workshop @ ICRA 2016
- · Workshop on Autonomous Robots and Multirobot Systems @ AAMAS 2016 Workshop on Artificial Intelligence and Robotics @ AAAI 2014, 2016
- · AAAI Robotics Fellowships 2015, 2016

INDUSTRY POSITIONS

Everis, Consulting, IT, Outsourcing & Professional Services, Lisbon, Portugal

September 2007 - February 2008

· Junior Consultant

Mercer Human Resource Consulting, Lisbon, Portugal

April 2006 – September 2006

· Part-time Collaborator

PUBLICATIONS